To analyze that given algorithm, we need to know with which inputs and the algorithm takes less time,
like performing well for the less time and which input the algorithms take a long time.
We have already seen that the algorithm can be represented in the form of an expression.
That means that we present the algorithm with multiple expression one for the case where it takes less
time and the other for the case where it takes more time.
In general, the first case is called the best case.
So the best case, that algorithm takes the least time.
OK.
And the second case is called the worst case for the algorithm to analyze an algorithm.
We need some kind of syntax that forms the base of for asymptotic as some static analysis or annotation.
There are three types of analysis the worst case, the best case and the average case.
OK.
So the worst case defines the input for which the algorithm takes a long time.
This is the slowest time to complete.
This is the worst case scenario.
Input is one of where one for which the algorithm runs the slowest.
OK, so worst case where the computer or the algorithm need many time.
I need the longest time or the slowest time and to be completed.
The best case defines the input for which the algorithm takes the least time.
This is the fastest time to complete.
So the best case algorithm that takes the least time to be accomplished?
OK.
Average case provides a prediction about the running time of the algorithm run algorithm, many times
using many different inputs that came out come from some distribution that generates generates these
AMP compute.
The total running time and divide by the number of trials assume that the input is random.
So this well, that is according to the input and that generated thanks and the average time the average
case is is or the average time is varying between the lower bound and the upper bound.
So the upper bound correspond to the worst case and the lower bound represents the best case.
For example, if you have an algorithm that can, you write it to be accomplished in one second.
So the lower bound would be one second.
And you can make another algorithm that perform the same action in 10 seconds.
So the lowest the least time is one second.
So it is the lower bound and the upper bound, which is the worst case is 10 seconds.
The average time is between one and ten seconds.
OK.
For other algorithms.
So the worst case is in seconds and the the best case is one second.
OK.
In the same way, 40 a given algorithm, we can represent the best, worst and the average cases in
form of expression as an example.
Let f of and be that a function which represent the given algorithm.
So f that have and the squared plus 500 is the worst case compared with the F and that have an plus
and plus five hundred.
Similarly, for the average case, the expression defines the input in which the algorithm takes the
average running time or memory you remember as an order, the end or the order of N in the function
increase that we're seeing or the or the like.
The algorithm speed to be executed will be decreased.
So as we move in the order of N and when we increase the order of N like and power one and power two
and three the worst, the algorithm is going to be OK.
As an order decreased their algorithm.
The algorithm performance and execution is increased.
OK.
So the least an order that best algorithm you.